<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>timothyelder.com</title>
    <link>https://timothyelder.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on timothyelder.com</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© {year}</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://timothyelder.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Chicago</title>
      <link>https://timothyelder.com/photo-projects/chicago-photos/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timothyelder.com/photo-projects/chicago-photos/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>https://timothyelder.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timothyelder.com/about/</guid>
      <description>Timothy Elder I&amp;rsquo;m a Research Associate at the Dartmouth Institute for Health Policy &amp;amp; Clinical Practice. I received my PhD in Sociology from the University of Chicago in 2024 and my research explores how knowledge is organized and used to inform expert work, particularly in the medical and scientific fields. My dissertation is a qualitative study that investigates how physicians and nurses working in Hospice and Palliative Medicine relate to their patients and interdigitate with medical experts from different specialties.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bikes</title>
      <link>https://timothyelder.com/bikes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timothyelder.com/bikes/</guid>
      <description>With the stress of finishing up my dissertation and applying to postdocs I did whatever I could to find some helpful distractions. I started working on vintage road bikes, particularly French ones. Working on bikes is a great distraction because, when compared to academia, it is a pristine domain of success and failure: if something breaks, it&amp;rsquo;s broken. If It&amp;rsquo;s fixed, it works. If you mess up, the bike lets you know, and the bike never lies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cameras</title>
      <link>https://timothyelder.com/cameras/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timothyelder.com/cameras/</guid>
      <description>Nikon D40 Michigan Ave. | YONGNUO 50mm F1.8 | f/200, ISO 200 Nikon FM10 Harper Memorial Library | Kodak Ultramax 400 Promontory Point | Kodak Ultramax 400 Holga 120N Hyde Park | Kodak Gold 200 Bat | Kodak Gold 200 Pentax MX Music Box Theater | Ilford HP5 Plus Black and White S. Wabash Ave. | Ilford HP5 Plus Black and White </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cv</title>
      <link>https://timothyelder.com/cv/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timothyelder.com/cv/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!DOCTYPE html&gt; cv github.com/timothyelder timothy.b.elder@dartmouth.edu 0000-0003-4164-1130 Download Vita TIMOTHY B. ELDER The Dartmouth Institute
Dartmouth College
Hanover, NH 03755
academic positions Research Associate, The Dartmouth Institute for Health Policy &amp; Clinical Practice, Geisel School of Medicine, Dartmouth College, 2024-2026. education PhD, Sociology, University of Chicago, 2024. Dissertation: Winning at a Losing Game - Divergent Ontologies and Shared Practices in Medicine. MA, Sociology, University of Chicago, 2018. BA, Cum Laude, Philosophy and Sociology, Kent State University, 2016.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>photos</title>
      <link>https://timothyelder.com/photos/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timothyelder.com/photos/</guid>
      <description>I developed an amateur interest in photography in high school and the enthusiasm was re-enflamed when I got a Nikon FM10 35mm film camera. Here are some examples of my own small contributions to the vast collection of images out there, shot with a number of different cameras.
Saieh Hall Promontory Point Chicago Board of Trade Bat Van Buren Street Station Somewhere on the Brown Line Lake Michigan </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>projects</title>
      <link>https://timothyelder.com/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timothyelder.com/projects/</guid>
      <description>My research investigates how networks of collaboration evolve and influence the work of professionals and experts, particularly in the scientific and medical fields. I use a variety of methods including open-ended unstructured interviews, ethnography, network and text analysis.
Collaboration and Decision-Making In Medical Specialties Growing specialization within professions leads to social differentiation and the development of specialty specific evaluation and knowledge. Using ethnographic and interview methods, my dissertation investigates how different medical specialties manage the care of terminally ill patients.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
