<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>timothyelder.com</title>
    <link>https://timothyelder.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on timothyelder.com</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© {year}</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://timothyelder.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Introduction and Overview</title>
      <link>https://timothyelder.com/plaintext/intro-and-overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timothyelder.com/plaintext/intro-and-overview/</guid>
      <description>Workshop Description and Objectives This working group is meant to give a short introductions to a set of plain text and open source tools for doing and writing up research. Many people have been exposed to these tools before, but the startup costs are non-negligible and we tend to fall back on the tools that are most ubiquitous rather than those that best suit our work. Unlike a traditional workshop at the University of Chicago, or a one time tutorial, we intend for this working group to allow interested students, post-docs and faculty to overcome the initial time investment and troubleshoot together to adopt a different and more appropriate set of tools for our research.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>https://timothyelder.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timothyelder.com/about/</guid>
      <description>Timothy Elder I&amp;rsquo;m a PhD candidate in Sociology at the University of Chicago and I study topics in the sociology of medicine, knowledge, social network analysis and death and dying. My dissertation investigates how physicians create plans of care for their patients: how they navigate conflict and build consensus, how they prognosticate and think about possible futures, and how they do all of this while honoring their obligations to ensure the well-being of their patients and colleagues is maintained.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cv</title>
      <link>https://timothyelder.com/cv/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timothyelder.com/cv/</guid>
      <description>Previous Next &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; Page: / You can download my CV here and the source code for it on my Github page here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://timothyelder.com/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timothyelder.com/projects/</guid>
      <description>My work is unified by an interest in how knowledge is organized and mustered to inform the practical work of social institutions like medicine and the academy.
Collaboration and Decision Making In Medical Specialties Using interview and ethnographic methods my dissertation research explores the relatively new medical sub-specialty of Hospice and Palliative Medicine, which is oriented toward the care of patients with chronic and life-limiting illness. I explore how these kinds of clinicians understand their role as consultants in hospitals and collaborate with their colleagues from other specialties.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
