<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>PlainText Working Group on timothyelder.com</title>
    <link>https://timothyelder.com/plaintext/</link>
    <description>Recent content in PlainText Working Group on timothyelder.com</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© {year}</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://timothyelder.com/plaintext/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Introduction and Overview</title>
      <link>https://timothyelder.com/plaintext/intro-and-overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timothyelder.com/plaintext/intro-and-overview/</guid>
      <description>Workshop Description and Objectives This working group is meant to give a short introductions to a set of plain text and open source tools for doing and writing up research. Many people have been exposed to these tools before, but the startup costs are non-negligible and we tend to fall back on the tools that are most ubiquitous rather than those that best suit our work. Unlike a traditional workshop at the University of Chicago, or a one time tutorial, we intend for this working group to allow interested students, post-docs and faculty to overcome the initial time investment and troubleshoot together to adopt a different and more appropriate set of tools for our research.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Terminal and Project Organization.</title>
      <link>https://timothyelder.com/plaintext/session-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timothyelder.com/plaintext/session-1/</guid>
      <description>Overview In the first session of the PlainText Working Group we are going to be covering two critical parts of working in plain text; using your computers command line or terminal and organizing a project directory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Math Typesetting</title>
      <link>https://timothyelder.com/plaintext/math-typesetting/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timothyelder.com/plaintext/math-typesetting/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Mathematical notation in a Hugo project can be enabled by using third party JavaScript libraries.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rich Content</title>
      <link>https://timothyelder.com/plaintext/rich-text/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://timothyelder.com/plaintext/rich-text/</guid>
      <description>Hugo ships with several Built-in Shortcodes for rich content, along with a Privacy Config and a set of Simple Shortcodes that enable static and no-JS versions of various social media embeds.
YouTube Privacy Enhanced Shortcode Twitter Simple Shortcode “In addition to being more logical, asymmetry has the advantage that its complete appearance is far more optically effective than symmetry.”
— Jan Tschichold pic.twitter.com/gcv7SrhvJb
&amp;mdash; Graphic Design History (@DesignReviewed) January 17, 2019 Vimeo Simple Shortcode </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
